Skand Vivek Dhar

skandvivek@gmail.com | 958-228-3216 | SRB-1C, SHIPRA RIVIERA, GYAN KHAND-3 INDIRAPURAM, GHAZIABAD, Uttar Pradesh 201014

Summary

I have over a decade of experience in reporting on various key social issues like Health, Education, and Child rights. I have received numerous fellowships from renowned organization including ICFJ and National Press Foundation during this tenure. Most of my fellowships were related to Child right. Currently, I am working as a special correspondent with leading Hindi daily Hindustan in New Delhi. Before joining Hindustan, I spent almost 10 years with another leading daily Rajasthan Patrika. I am well versed with the political economy of India and have very cordial relationships with bureaucrats and politicians.

Skills

- good rapport with Political leadership and bureaucrats.
- Thorough understanding of Political economy of the Republic of India.
- Extensive network with journalists in National capital and in Many states of Rajasthan.
- Ability to convey information in a clear, concise and conversational manner.
- Ability to interact professionally and build relationships.
- Strong research skills, including ability to navigate search engines.

Experience

Special Correspondent - Hindustan Media Ventures Ltd. (New Delhi, Delhi (UT))

January 2018 - Current

- I Cover Health and Education beat which includes ministry of Health and family welfare, Ministry of HRD as well.
- I have to keep eyes on political developments & Policy making and report accordingly.
- A key component of a my job is to conduct interviews of dignitaries including ministers and top bureaucrats.

Principal Correspondent - Rajasthan Patrika (New Delhi, Delhi (UT)) November 2010 - December 2017

- Won national award for Agriculture reporting in 2016 from Ministry of Agriculture, Government of India.
- Covered Rajasthan affairs both political and governmental from National capital New Delhi.

Sub editor to Chief sub editor - Rajasthan Patrika (Jaipur, RJ) April 2008 - November 2010

- I was based in jaipur and did local or state level stories during this tenure.
- Got my first National media fellowship from National foundation for India.

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Economics, Geography and English 2006

University of Allahabad, Allahabad

Master of Arts in Journalism

2008

Makhanlal Chaturvedi Rashtriya Patrakarita Avam Sanchar Vishwavidyalaya, Bhopal, MP

Honors

 Chaudhari Charan Singh excellence in agriculture reporting award 2015 by Ministry of Agriculture and farmer's welfare. I am the youngest reporter to have this award.

Fellowships

- Fellowship from the International Center for Journalist, the USA to work on Early Child development issues. It was a year-long fellowship. (12 Sep 2017 to 11 Sep 2018)
- Fellowship from Ministry of culture, Government of India to do research history of Beedi industry of Madhya Pradesh. (2012-14)
- National Media fellowship-2016 from Feji-Atree media fellowship.
- National Media Fellowship-2015 from Child right and you (CRY) 2015.
- J2J Lung Media fellowship-2014 By National Press Foundation, New York.
- National Media Fellowship-2013 to write on Tb among weavers.
- Panos South Asia's National Media Fellowship-2012 on Tobacco Control.
- 15th National Media Fellowship-2009 from National Foundation for India.

Personal Information

- Date of Birth: October 26th, 1985.
- Son of: Late Mr. Neel Ratan Dhar & Smt Sudarshan Shrivastava
- Marital Status: Married

References

- Mr. Declan Okpalaeke President, African Health Journalists association Nigeria.
- Mr. Arun Chauhan, Editor, Rajasthan Patrika, jaipur